A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices xFA116
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Field Offices - Paris, 1935-1976, undated; 1; 54.8 Cubic Feet 149 document cases
  - Prewar, 1922-1941; 1; 46 Boxes; 28 cubic feet
    - Prewar - Correspondence, 1.01
      - IHD General - Rockefeller Institute, 1936-1939 (Box 39, Folder 483)
      - IHD General - Schools of Nursing - Procedure, 1927-1938 (Box 39, Folder 484)
      - IHD General - Study of European Institutes of Hygiene, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 485)
      - IHD General - Syphilis Study, 1938-1939 (Box 39, Folder 486)
      - IHD General - Travel of Visiting Health Officials and Training of Health Workers, 1924-1928 (Box 39, Folder 487)
      - IHD General - Travel of Visiting Health Officials and Training of Health Workers, 1929-1938 (Box 39, Folder 488)
      - IHD General - Travel of Visiting Health Officials and Training of Health Workers, 1929-1938 (Box 39, Folder 489)
      - IHD General - Yellow Fever Cooperation with Office International Hygiene Publique, 1934-1939 (Box 39, Folder 490)
      - SS Project Memoranda and Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 40, Folder 491)
        Kittredge, Tracy B. to New York - 1939-1940 Draft of Memorandum on Refugee Scholars - January 23, 1940
      - SS Project Memoranda and Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 40, Folder 492)
      - General China Program, 1937-1940 (Box 40, Folder 493)
        Agricultural Economics - Nanking University - 1937-1938 Commission on Medical Education - 1938 Hsing-ya Medical College - 1940 Nankai Institute of Economics - 1939 National Central University - 1938 National Council for Rural Reconstruction - 1938-1939 Yen, James C. - 1940
      - General Cite Universitaire - (General Support and International House), 1926-1940 (Box 40, Folder 494)
      - General Cite Universitaire - (General Support and International House), 1926-1940 (Box 40, Folder 495)
    - Prewar - Financial Material, 1.02
      - Commission for the Prevention of Tuberculosis in France, 1917-1922 (Box 41, Folder 496)
        Audit Reports - (6) - 1917-1922 Salary Increases - 1919-1920
      - International Education Board - Audit Reports, 1926-1927; 2 items (Box 41, Folder 497)
      - Rockefeller Foundation - Audit Reports, 1923-1929; 8 items (Box 41, Folder 498)
      - Rockefeller Foundation - Audit Reports, 1935-1939; 5 items (Box 41, Folder 499)
      - Rockefeller Foundation - Audit Reports, 1935-1939; 5 items (Box 41, Folder 500)
      - Societe Immobiliere Las Baume-Haussman - Correspondence, 1926-1928, 1934-1941 (Box 41, Folder 501)
      - Appropriation Book - Advances, 1925 (Box 42, Folder 502)
      - Appropriation Book, 1925 (Box 42, Folder 503)
      - I. E. B. Appropriation Book, 1926-1927 (Box 42, Folder 504)
      - I. E. B. / D. M. E. Account Book - Literature, 1927 (Box 42, Folder 505)
      - Appropriation Book, 1928 (Box 42, Folder 506)
      - Budget and Appropriation Book, 1928 (Box 42, Folder 507)
      - Account Book - Laboratory Allotments, Developmental Aid, Research Aid, 1929-1930 (Box 42, Folder 508)
      - Salary Accounts - Account Book, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 509)
      - Central Administration Staff Forms - 1918-1940 Payroll Book - 1928-1941, 1918-1941 (Box 042A)
      - Central Administration Staff Forms - 1918-1940 Payroll Book - 1928-1941, 1918-1941 (Box 042A)
    - Prewar - Reports, 1.03
      - Bailey, Charles A. - "Public Health in Spain", April 1926; 2 copies (Box 43, Folder 510)
      - Bevier, George - "Public Health in Austria", 1925 (Box 43, Folder 511)
      - Bevier, George and Gunn, Selskar - "Public Health in Ireland", 1924 (Box 43, Folder 512)
      - Collins, Ralph K. - "Public Health in Turkey", 1926 (Box 44, Folder 513)
      - Collins, R. K. - "Report of the Station for Field Studies in Malaria at Petritch", 1928 (Box 44, Folder 514)
      - Eversole, H.O. - "Medical Education in the Baltic States", 1923; 2 volumes (Box 44, Folder 515)
      - Eversole, H.O. - "Medical Education in the Baltic States", 1923; 2 volumes (Box 44, Folder 516)
      - Eversole, H.O. - "Medical Education in Constantinople", 1923 (Box 44, Folder 517)
      - Gantt, W. Horsley - "A Medical Review of Soviet Russia", 1926 (Box 44, Folder 518)
      - Gregg, Alan - "Survey of Iceland", 1927 (Box 44, Folder 519)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. - "Memoranda on Public Health in Czecholslovakia", 1920 (Box 44, Folder 520)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. - "Public Health in Algeria", 1925 (Box 45, Folder 521)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. - "Public Health in Bulgaria", 1923 (Box 45, Folder 522)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. - "Public Health in Hungary", 1924 (Box 45, Folder 523)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. - "Public Health in Yugoslavia", 1924 (Box 46, Folder 524)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. - "Public Health in Norway, Sweden and Demark", 1924 (Box 46, Folder 525)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. and Mitchell, W. Leland - "Public Health in Rumania", 1925 (Box 46, Folder 526)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. and Rose, Wickliffe - "Public Health Situation in Czechoslovakia", 1919 (Box 47, Folder 527)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. - "Report on Poland", 1922 (Box 47, Folder 528)
      - Gunn, Selskar M. - "Report of a Visit of Investigation to Czechoslovakia, June 1-14, 1919" (Box 47, Folder 529)
      - Information Service, N.Y. - "Medical Education in the Baltic States", 1924 (Box 47, Folder 530)
      - Information Service, N.Y. - "Medical Education in Iceland", 1924 (Box 47, Folder 531)
      - Information Service, N.Y. - "Medical Education in Iceland", 1924 (Box 47, Folder 532)
      - Information Service, N.Y. - "Medical Education in Italy", 1924 (Box 47, Folder 533)
      - Information Service, N.Y. - "Medical Education in Norway", 1923 (Box 47, Folder 534)
      - Information Service, N.Y. - "Medical Education in Poland", 1923-1924 (Box 47, Folder 535)
      - Information Service, N.Y. - "Medical Education in Portugal", 1924 (Box 47, Folder 536)
      - Information Service, N.Y. - "Miscellaneous Material on Conditions in Russia with Special Reference to Medical Education", 1927 (Box 48, Folder 537)
      - International Health Division - Paris Office Annual Report - Volume III, 1930 (Box 48, Folder 538)
      - Mitchell, W. Leland - "Report on the Public Health Situation in Southern Yugoslavia (Macedonia)", 1930 (Box 48, Folder 539)
      - Mitchell, W. Leland - "Visit to Southern Yugoslavia, July 6-20, 1927" (Box 48, Folder 540)
      - Pearce, Richard M. - "Medical Education in France", 1925 (Box 48, Folder 541)
      - Pearce, Richard M. - "Medical Education in France" - Appendix, 1925 (Box 48, Folder 542)
      - Pearce, Richard M. - "Medical Education in Wales", 1926 (Box 49, Folder 543)
      - Pearce, Richard M. - "Notes on Tarn-Et-Garrone", 1928 (Box 49, Folder 544)
      - Pearce, Richard M. - "Report on the Department of Tarn-Et-Garrone", 1926 (Box 49, Folder 545)
      - Rose, Wickliffe and Gunn, Selskar - "Public Health in Czechoslovakia", 1921 (Box 49, Folder 546)
      - Taylor, Richard M. - "Report on the Department of Aisne", 1927 (Box 49, Folder 547)
  - Postwar, 1945-1959; 2; 81 Boxes; 42 cubic feet
    Programs included are Medical Sciences (MS), Natural Sciences and Agriculture (NSA), International Health Division (IHD), Division of Medicine and Public Health (DMPH). There is a section designated "General" which includes non-divisional correspondence.
    Postwar correspondence includes considerable correspondence with the New York office. Some of this material may be duplicated in New York Office files. Files involving fellowships are unique, those in New York having been destroyed through 1954 according to policy. Major subjects are public health, nursing, sanitary engineering, psychiatry, neurology, physiology. Correspondents include Arturi Virtanen, Arne Tiselius, Walter R. Hess, Ragnar, Granit, Jean Piaget. Correspondence is mainly in English.
    Files in two subseries (correspondence, financial material) numbered continuously. Correspondence is arranged by program, within program alphabetically by country, within country alphabetically by title (person, subject, or institution). Strict chronological arrangement is followed withing folders, reports and reprints are filed with correspondence unless numbers or dimensions necessitated a second folder. Files may include grants, general correspondence, declinations, or fellowships all in the same folder, that is all correspondence with a given person or institution is generally filed together regardless of its nature.
    Related material can be found in the Rockefeller Foundation's projects files RG 1.1, under European country numbers, especially 500 France and 700 Europe.
    - Postwar - Correspondence, 2.01
      - MS Austria, 1945-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Innsbruck University - (medical faculty) - 1947-1953 Job, Carl - (fellowship, neurophysiology) - 1949-1953 Pateisky, Kurt - (fellowship, neurology) - 1948-1952 Strasbourg University - Medical Clinic B - 1945 Urban, Hurbert J. - (psychiatry) - 1947-1953 Vienna University - (medical faculty) - 1947-1952
      - MS Belgium, 1946-1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Brull, L. - (physiology) - 1947-1954 van Campenhout, E. - (anatomy and histology) - 1947-1951 Gobaerts, Paul - (travel, medicine and administration) - 1946-1949 Lambrechts, A. - (travel, pediatrics) - 1947-1950 de Muylder, Edgard A. - (fellowships, obstetrics and gynecology)
      - MS Canada, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Buck, Carol - (fellowship, clinical preventive medicine) - 1950-1952 Toronto University - (visits) - 1950, 1954
      - MS Czechoslovakia, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Bedrna, Jan and Fingerland, Antonin - (travel, surgery and pathology) - 1947-1949 Carsky, Konstantin - (travel, surgery) - 1947 National and University Library - (equipment) - 1947 Servit, Z. D. - (travel, neurology) - 1947-1948
      - MS Czechoslovakia - Charles University, Prague - Jirasek, Arnold - (neurosurgery), 1945-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - MS Denmark, 1946-1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Boesen, Ib - (fellowship, pediatrics) - 1947-1951 Busch, E. - (travel, neurosurgery) - 1946-1947 Hansen, Anders Emil Tybjcerg - (fellowship, internal medicine) - 1948-1951 Helweg-Larsen, Hans Frederick - (fellowship, medical statistics and genetics) - 1948-1951
      - MS Denmark, 1945-1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Schlegel, Jorgen V. - (fellowship, gynecology) - 1947-1953 Stokholm, Harry - (fellowship, psychiatry) - 1949-1952 Wels-Fogh, Jorgen - (fellowship, internal medicine) - 1950-1951 Winkel-Smith, C.C. - (fellowship, pediatric surgery) - (equipment) - 1945-1951
      - MS England, 1945-1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        British Pediatric Assocation - (general correspondence) - 1947-1954 Causey, Gilbert - (travel, anatomy) - 1950 Charing Cross Hospital Medical School - (hospital planning) - 1948-1949 Dodds, Gladys - (travel, gynecology) - 1949-1950 Garrod, L.P. - (bacteriology) - 1948 Kiernander, Basil - (travel, pediatrics and physiotherapy) - 1948-1950 McMichael, John - (Postgraduate Medical School of London) - (equipment) - 1947-1948 Medical Research Council - (serological genetics) - 1947 Nixon, W.C.W. - (travel, gynecology) - 1946-1951 Oldfield, R.C. - (travel, experimental psychology) - 1948-1952 Pilcher, R.S. - (travel, surgery) - 1949 Royal Society of Medicine - Central Medical Library Bureau - 1945 St. Thomas' Hospital - Sherrington School of Physiology - 1948-1951 Strangeways Research Laboratory - Jacobson, Werner - (cell biology) - 1947, 1950
      - MS England - Medical Research Council - Fellowships, 1945-1951 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - MS England - Tavistock Institute of Human Relations, 1945-1954 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - MS England - Tavistock Institute of Human Relations, 1945-1954 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - MS England - Tavistock Institute of Human Relations, 1945-1954 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - MS Finland, 1946-1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        Hartiala, Kaarlo - (fellowship, physiology) - 1947-1950 Helsinki University - Faculty of Medicine - 1946-1949 Kaila, Martti - (travel, psychiatry) - 1951 Wager, Odd - (fellowship, bacteriology) - 1950-1953 Wasastjerna, Cort - (fellowship, internal medicine) - 1950-1952
      - MS France, 1947-1953 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        Alloiteau, J.J. - (pediatrics, endocrinology) - 1945-1947 Delmas-Marsalet, P. - (travel, psychiatry) - 1948 Douboucet, Nadia - (anesthesiology) - 1947-1950 Eschapasse, Henry - (fellowship, experimental surgery) - 1948-1953 Gastout, Henri - (travel, neurology) - 1948-1949 Gerard, Raymond - (fellowship, cardiology) - 1948-1950 Ginglinger, Albert - (travel, obstetrics) - 1949-1950 Heuyer, Georges - (child psychiatry, books) - 1948-1951 Hopitaux de Paris - (equipment) - 1948
      - MS France, 1945-1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
        Levy-Bruhl, Odile - (fellowship, child psychiatry) - 1950-1955 Lezine, Irene - (travel, child psychiatry) - 1948 Medical Publications - (actions) - 1946-1947 Metras, Henri - (thoracic surgery) - 1948-1950 Montpelier Laboratory of Angiocardiography - (Giraud, Gaston) - 1949 Mosinger, Michel - (neurobiology) - 1945 Nancy University - Institute of Hygiene - 1946 Policard, A. - (Lyon University) - (histology) - 1949-1950 Scherrer, Jean - (fellowship, neurophysiology) - 1948-1953
      - MS France, 1945-1953 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        Smirnoff, Victor - (fellowship, child psychiatry) - 1950-1953 Stahl, Jules - (travel, clinical medicine) - (action) - 1946 Strasbourg University - Surgical Clinic - (action) - 1947 Vallery-Radot, Pasteur - Les Editions Medicales Flammarion - 1945-1948
      - MS France - College de France - Courrier, Robert - (equipment), 1944-1956 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - MS France - College de France - Courrier, Robert - (equipment), 1944-1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - MS France - Metz, Bernard - (physiology), 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - MS France - Paris University, 1945-1953 (Box 3, Folder 20)
        Institute of Parasitology - (Gaillard, H.) - 1948 Neurosurgery - (Le Beau, Jacques) - 1945-1953 Vincent, Clovis - (neurosurgery) - 1946-1948
      - MS France - Rademaker, Marianne - (fellowship, anesthesia), 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - MS France - Toulouse University, 1948-1953 (Box 3, Folder 22)
        Department of Anesthesia - 1948-1953 Department of Surgery - 1949-1950
      - MS Germany, 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 23)
        Bargmann, Wolfgang - (travel, anatomy) - 1950 Fritz-Seeman, Walter - (psychiatry) - 1948-1951 Reiter, Melchior - (fellowship, pharmacology) - 1948-1950 Schiebler, Theodore H. - (fellowship, histology) - 1949-1952 Zahn, Rudolf - (fellowship, physiology) - 1948-1951 Zollner, Nepomuk - (medical education) - 1950-1951
      - MS Holland, 1945-1950 (Box 4, Folder 24)
        Amsterdam University - Psychosomatic Unit - 1947-1948 Amsterdam University - Van Longhem, J.J. - (Institute of Hygiene) - 1945 Emergency Grant-in-Aid Fun - 1945-1947 Rodbard, J.A. - (internal medicine) - 1947-1950
      - MS India, 1949-1952 (Box 4, Folder 25)
        Hanadive, Kamal Jaynsing - (fellowship, pathology) - 1949-1952 Mehrotra, Ram Mohan Lal - (fellowship, pathology) - 1949-1951 Mitra, Nripendra Lal - (fellowship, anatomy) - 1949-1952 Shah, Upendra N. - (fellowship, surgery) - 1950-1952
      - MS Italy, 1947-1958 (Box 4, Folder 26)
        Bologna University - Clinic for Nervous and Mental Diseases - 1949-1958 Bovet, Daniel - (travel, allergy study) - (action) - 1947 Dalla Volta, Amedeo - (travel, psychology) - 1949-1950 Fuortes, Michelangelo G.F. - (fellowship, neurophysiology) - 1948-1955 Galliotti, Flori Erigo - (travel, pediatrics) - (action) - 1949 Giotti, Alberto - (fellowship, pharmacy) - 1948-1950
      - MS Italy - Gualtierotti, Torquato - (fellowship, physiology), 1948-1952 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - MS Italy, 1948-1956 (Box 4, Folder 28)
        Lombroso, Cesare - (fellowship, pediatrics) - 1948-1950 Marsan, Cosimo Ajmone - (fellowship, neurophysiology) - 1948-1951 Marzi, Alberto - (travel, experimental psychology) - 1948 Mora, Giorgio - (fellowship, child psychology) - 1951-1956 Morin, Ferdinando - (fellowship, neurology) - 1948-1954 Naples University - General Biology and Human Genetics - 1951-1954 Naples University - Pediatrics - 1948 Turin University - Clinic for Nervous and Mental Diseases - 1948-1951
      - MS Japan - Tasaki, Ichigi - (fellowship, nerve physiology), 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - MS Yugoslavia, 1946-1954 (Box 4, Folder 30)
        Cupic, Vukan - (fellowship, pediatrics) - 1947-1953 Djankovic, Hugo and Skrivaneli, Niko - (travel, surgery and pediatrics) - 1946-1954 Lavric, Bozidar and Brecelj, Bogdan - (travel, surgery and orthopaedics) - 1950-1952
      - MS Yugoslavia - Martinovitch, Petar - (travel, experimental biology), 1947-1957 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - MS Norway, 1945-1955 (Box 5, Folder 32)
        Asa, Arrid - (fellowship, psychology) - 1949-1952 Blystad, Wilhelm - (fellowship, pediatrics) - 1948-1950 Cammermeyer, Johan W.H. - (fellowship, neuropathology) - 1946-1948 Eker, Reidar - (pathology) - 1947-1948 Oslo University - Department of Pathology - 1949-1952 Rasmussen, Hakon - (cardiology) - 1946-1947 Terminated grants - (miscellaneous actions and correspondence) - 1945-1951 Wergeland, Hjalmar - (child psychiatry) - 1955
      - MS Poland, 1945-1952 (Box 5, Folder 33)
        Grzybowski, Marjan - (travel, dermatology) - 1947-1950 Kossakowski, Jan - (pediatric surgery) - 1947-1948 Terminated Grants - (miscellaneous actions and correspondence) Tuszkiewicz, Alfred and Klisiecki, A. - (travel, internal medicine and physiology) - 1947-1948 Wierzuchowski, Mieczystaw - (travel, internal medicine) - 1945-1952
      - MS South Africa - Streeten, David H.P. - (fellowship, pharmacology), 1950-1954 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      - MS Spain, 1949-1953 (Box 5, Folder 35)
        Bachs Fornes, Agustin - (fellowship, neurosurgery) - 1949-1953 Calvo Carra, Wenceslao - (fellowship, neuropathology) - 1949-1952
      - MS Sweden, 1946-1952 (Box 5, Folder 36)
        Astrom, Karl-Erik - (fellowship, physiology) - 1947-1950 Afzelius-Alm, Leslie - (fellowship, virus research) - 1946-1950 Bjurstedt, Anders Gustav Hilding - (fellowship, physiology) - 1949-1952 Radner, Stig - (fellowship, cardiac-respiratory physiology) - 1950-1952 Sjovall, Thorsten - (fellowship, psychiatry) - 1948-1952 Tegner, Carl Lennart - (fellowship, psychiatry) - 1949-1951 Terminated grants - (miscellaneous actions and correspondence) - 1948-1950
      - MS Switzerland - Geneva University - Laboratory of Applied Neurophysiology - (Monnier, Marcel), 1948-1954 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - MS Switzerland - Hess, Walter Rudolf - (neurophysiology), 1946-1952 (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - MS Switzerland, 1948-1952 (Box 6, Folder 39)
        Oberholzer, Rudi J.H. - (fellowship, neurophysiology) - 1948-1952 Zellweger, Hans - (travel, pediatrics) - 1951
      - MS United States, 1941-1951 (Box 6, Folder 40)
        Bloch, Hubert - (travel, psychosomatic medicine) - 1950-1951 Terminated grants - (miscellaneous actions and correspondence) - 1947-1950
      - NSA Argentina - Albani, Felix - (fellowship, meteorology), 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - NSA Austria - Vienna University, 1951-1954 (Box 6, Folder 42)
        Mainx, Felix - Institute of General Biology - (actions) - 1951-1953 Wessely, Friedrich - Second Chemical Laboratory - 1951-1954
      - NSA Belgium, 1946-1954 (Box 6, Folder 43)
        Buchthal, Fritz - (neurophysiology) - 1946-1953 DeDuve, Christian - (fellowship, biochemistry) - 1947-1954 Desireux, Victor - (fellowship, biochemistry) - 1949-1952 Liebecq, Claude - (biochemistry) - 1952-1954 Terminated grants - (miscellaneous actions and correspondence) - 1949-1954
      - NSA Brazil, 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 44)
        Autuori, M.P. - (travel) - 1957 Prado, Jose Leal - (fellowship, physiological chemistry) - 1954-1955
      - NSA Denmark, 1945-1954 (Box 6, Folder 45)
        Copenhagen University - European Conferences on Microbial Genetics - 1950-1952 Kalckar, H.M. - (medical physiology) - 1947-1953 Kruhoffer, Paul - (fellowship, physiology) - 1948-1949 Linderstrom-Lang, K. - (chemistry, equipment) - 1947-1951 Schonheyder, F. - (biochemistry) - 1945-1953 Terminated grants - (miscellaneous actions and correspondence) - 1945-1954
      - NSA England, 1942-1956 (Box 6, Folder 46)
        Creeth, James M. - (fellowship, biochemistry) - 1952-1953 Finean, J.B. - (fellow, biochemistry) - 1955 Fraenkel, G. - (insect nutrition) - 1942, 1947 Hanson, Emmeline Jean - (fellowship, biology) - 1947-1954 Leeds University - Broadhead, Edward - (travel, entomology) - 1955-1956 Medawar, Peter Brian - (fellowship, physiology) - 1948-1949 Oxford University - Pathology - 1946-1955 Randall, J.T. - (biophysics) - 1948-1955 Tait, James F. - (biochemistry) - 1953-1954 University College, London - Biometry - 1946-1953
      - NSA England - Terminated grants - (actions and copies only), 1945-1957 (Box 6, Folder 47)
      - NSA Finland, 1946-1958 (Box 7, Folder 48)
        Rautanen, Niilo Sakari - (fellowship, biochemistry) - 1951-1952 Terminated grants - (actions and copies only) - 1946-1958
      - NSA France, 1949-1956 (Box 7, Folder 49)
        Asselineau, Jean - (fellowship, chemistry) - 1951-1955 Bussard, Alain - (fellowship, immunochemistry) - 1949-1952 Camus, Guy Charles Edward - (fellowship, plant physiology) - 1949-1956
      - NSA France - Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique - 1946-1954 and Report - 1945, 1945-1954 (Box 7, Folder 50)
      - NSA France - Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique - 1946-1954 and Report - 1945, 1945-1954 (Box 7, Folder 51)
      - NSA France - Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique - Colloques, 1950-1959 (Box 7, Folder 52)
      - NSA France, 1948-1956 (Box 7, Folder 53)
        Cerf, Roger - (fellowship, physics) - 1950-1951 Clauser, Hubert - (fellowship, physiological chemistry) - 1952 College de France - Laboratory of General Biochemistry - 1949-1955 Coursaget, Jean - (travel, isotopes and biology) - 1950-1956 Enselme, Jean - (biological chemistry) - 1952 Gros, Francois - (fellowship, biochemistry) - 1953-1955 Institut National d'Hygiene - 1948-1954
      - NSA France - Institut Pasteur, 1945-1959 (Box 7, Folder 54)
      - NSA France, 1946-1956 (Box 8, Folder 55)
        Lyon University - (natural sciences) - 1946-1949 Marseille Station Marine d'Endoume - (marine biology) - 1950-1954 Marseille University - Chouteau, Jacques - (physiology) - 1951-1954 Marseille University - Derrien, Yves - (biological chemistry) - 1948-1953 Marseille University - Desnuelle, Pierre - (biology) - 1947-1952 Montpelier Institute of Chemistry - 1950-1956 Nancy University - Bourbaki Group - (mathematics) - 1948-1951 Nancy University - Laboratory of Biological Chemistry - 1953-1955 Nancy University - School of Industrial and Mineral Chemistry - 1951-1953 Paris University - Ephrussi Boris - (genetics) - 1949-1954 Paris University - Gallien, L. - (animal biology) - 1951-1955 Paris University - Institut Henri Poincare - (mathematics) - 1949-1952 Paris University - Roucayrol, Jean-Claude - (biophysics) - 1949-1952 Paris University - Terminated grants - (actions and copies only) - 1948-1954
      - NSA France - Paris University - Laboratory of Biological Chemistry, 1947-1955 (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - NSA France - Paris University - Laboratory of Biological/Physical Chemistry, 1949-1956 (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - NSA France, 1947-1953 (Box 8, Folder 58)
        Schaeffer, Pierre A.G. - (fellowship, genetics) - 1949-1953 Strasbourg University - Chevallier, Andre - (biophysics) - 1949-1951 Strasbourg University - Institute of Chemical Biology - (Boivin, Andre) - 1947-1949 Strasbourg University - Wolff, Etienne - (zoology and embryology) - 1948-1949
      - NSA France - Toulouse University - Laboratory of Physical Chemistry - 1951-1952 and Reports (2) - 1950, 1950-1952 (Box 8, Folder 59)
      - NSA Germany, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 60)